evga.com 2018-12-24

# EVGA - Legal - Privacy Policy

The protection of your personal data is of highest importance to us. This Privacy Policy tells you about the information we collect from you in accordance with the regulations set forth in the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) when you use, purchase our products or services or benefit from other services (e.g. Forum /Community) from our website www.evga.com.

With checking the box "Yes, I accept EVGA's Privacy Policy" you agree to the processing of your personal data as set out below.

  1. ###### Applicability

This privacy policy applies to the processing of personal data of data subjects in the context of using our website, purchasing goods and services via our online-shop and to all monitoring of data subject's behavior during the visit of our website.

  2. ###### Controller

Controller of the website www.evga.com and the online-shop included therein is EVGA Corporation., located at 408 Saturn Street, Brea, CA 92821. For European privacy policy, [click here](https://eu.evga.com/legal/privacy/).

  3. ###### Data Protection Officer

For any privacy issues or for further information on EVGA's data processing activities, outside of European Union,please contact the data protection officer of EVGA:

    * David Risser
    * 408 Saturn Street, Brea, CA 92821
    * E-Mail [dataprotection@evga.com](mailto:dataprotection@evga.com)
    * Phone 714-528-4500
    * Fax 714-528-4501
  4. ###### Scope of collection and storage of personal data

We are processing personal data solely for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract or for support reasons. Moreover we are processing personal data were processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data.

Not providing personal data may mean that EVGA is unable to provide services to you. In the following sec 5. – 14. it is described how we process personal data and how such processing is justified.

  5. ###### Visiting our website

If you visit our websites we automatically collect and store the following information in so-called server log files which your browser automatically transmits and saves until automated deletion:

    * browser type/version
    * used operating system
    * referrer URL
    * IP address
    * host name of the accessing computer
    * time of query

The lawful processing of these data occurs for the purposes of enabling use of the website, for system security, for technical administration of the network infrastructure and for optimization of our website.

  6. ###### Usage of personal data

In accordance with the principle of data avoidance and data economy, we only collect personal data on our website when it is either required for your desired purpose, we are obligated to do so due to legal regulations or contracts, if we have a legitimate interest and/or if you voluntarily give us your consent.

We keep your personal data stored until the completion of the transaction or the enquiry, for the duration of a warranty and moreover to the extent and for the duration necessary to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject, for archiving purposes and for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. In case you create an account we keep your order information until you delete your account, provided that all transactions under your account are completed and closed.

    1. ###### Purchasing goods and services

When you purchase products or services (e.g. extended warranties) from our online-shop, we ask you for your:

      * Login name, Password, Customer ID
      * full name
      * address (billing and shipping address)
      * telephone number(s)
      * email address
      * payment information, such as PayPal account info (i.e. name, address, email address and transaction ID) etc. – (optional).

Your information is used for the performance of the concluded contract and potential warranties and is stored in our order processing system hosted by our parent company EVGA Corp. in the United States. We have concluded the respective data processing agreements within the group companies.

Your credit card details are passed to a third-party payment processor.

    2. ###### Customer Support, RMA

If you send enquiries to our customer support or technical support (e.g. for RMA - Return Merchandise Authorization purposes), as well as for complaints and suggestions or for the purpose of rating our service we collect the following data:

      * full name
      * address (billing and shipping address)
      * telephone number(s)
      * email address 
      * payment information, such as PayPal account info (i.e. Name, address, email address and transaction ID) etc. – (optional)
      * invoices, credit notes and statements according to the respective services/products in case you want to register a product (optional)
      * EVGA Folding Name (optional, at time of account creation)
      * Social Media IDs (optional, at time of account creation)
      * Shirt Size (optional, at time of account creation). 

Such data entered into the contact form, including the stated contact data, are stored for the purpose of dealing with your enquiry and in case of additional enquiries.

Your information is used in order to process your request and is stored in our order processing system hosted by our parent company EVGA Corp. in the United States. Moreover, customer care services will be carried out from our group companies EVGA GmbH, Germany and Propellerhead Support Services, United Kingdom. We have concluded the respective data processing agreements within the group companies and with third parties.

    3. ###### Registering of software products

Certain software products which are offered for download via our website, will request the following personal data in order to complete the installation process and register the product to your account

      * IP address
      * full name,
      * e-mail address

Your information is used for the performance of the concluded contract and potential warranties and is stored in our order processing system hosted by our parent company EVGA Corp. in the United States. We have concluded the respective data processing agreements within the group companies.

We use such data for the purpose of our legitimate interest in order to analyze the usage and capability of our products in order to improve our products and support services.

  7. ###### Forum Postings / Communities

We store your personal information if you voluntarily submit the information to us for the purpose of using our forums or communities. You can edit your profil e.g. with the following data:

    * name
    * birthday (optional)
    * location (optional)
    * interests (optional)
    * occupation (optional)

Since we do not monitor the postings, we explicitly warn you, that submitting personal data in communities /forums is never safe and security or the exclusion of any third part access to those postings may never be excluded.

The information posted via forums/communities will be stored on servers hosted by our parent company EVGA Corp. in the United States. We have concluded the respective data processing agreements within the group companies.

In case you ask us to delete your EVGA account please note, that the content of your forum postings will still be visible but tied to an anonymized profile. Unless required under applicable law EVGA is not obliged to delete the content of forum postings.

  8. ###### Gaming & Promotions

EVGA offers several promotions on the website. The participation is at user's sole discretion. However, participation in these offers requires the tracking of personal data as described below.

We will delete all data entered during the sign-up process for promotions after the closing date of the respective promotion except of data regarding the winner. Such data will be deleted if storage is no longer required to comply with statutory provisions and legal obligations to which EVGA is subject or for other legitimate interests of EVGA. Unless stipulated otherwise the deletion of data will be carried out following a best efforts practice regularly within 30 days after the completion of the respective promotion.

In case not specified otherwise in the respective game's or promotion's Terms and Conditions, EVGA tracks the following personal data:

    1. ###### Monthly Folding Promotion

We track user's

      * Folding name
      * e-mail address
      * shipping address (only applicable for the winner)
    2. ###### Live Giveaway Promotion

In case you subscribe to our weekly give away promotion in our live stream we log

      * Gaming name
      * social media names 
      * e-mail address 
      * shipping address (only applicable for the winner). 
    3. ###### Social Media and Gaming Promotions

In case you subscribe to any social Media and gaming promotions we log

      * e-mail address
      * Customer ID
      * Gaming name
      * Solider name from game
      * Steam name
      * social media names
      * shipping address (only applicable for the winner)
    4. ###### Press request for free products

In case we offer products free of charge for press reviews to the audience we will log the following data

      * full name
      * company
      * shipping address
      * telephone number(s)
      * email address

We will store the data regularly for 1 year after shipping the requested article, provided storage is no longer required to comply with statutory provisions and legal obligations to which EVGA is subject or for other legitimate interests of EVGA.

  9. ###### Newsletter

If you subscribe to our newsletter through your email address, we will use your email address beyond the implementation of the contract for our own advertising purposes until you unsubscribe from the newsletter. You may review and change the newsletter settings if you login to your account ("MY EVGA").

  10. ###### Location based services

In order to route you to the correct national landing page we use the location data submitted by your Browser. We will solely localize the country but not your exact location. You will be able to deny such localization in your personal browser settings at any time.

  11. ###### Disclosure of Personal data, Transfer to third parties

Personal data will not be disclosed to third parties unless you have given your consent with such disclosure, the disclosure is necessary for compliance with legal obligations to which EVGA is subject or when the disclosure is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by EVGA or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.

EVGA only transfers data to states outside of the EU/EEA provided the recipient guaranties a standard of data protection comparable to European standards (e.g. by agreeing to approved contractual clauses, intragroup agreements or other measures designed to ensure that the recipients of personal data protect them).

Besides these transfers mentioned under this Privacy Policy no transmission of data to third parties does take place unless you have given your explicit permission. A transmission of data to third parties for commercial purposes does not take place. We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

    1. ###### Sharing of Personal Data within the EVGA Group

Personal data may be transferred or disclosed to any company within the EVGA Group. EVGA Group means (EVGA Cooperatie U.A., EVGA Corporation (USA), EVGA Corporation (Taiwan), EVGA Hong Kong Company Ltd., EVGA GmbH).

    2. ###### Sharing of Personal Data with Service Providers

We use third-party courier companies to deliver your goods and we share with them your name, address and telephone number in order to complete the delivery.

We use PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. et Cie, S.C.A. Société en Commandite par Actions Registered Office: 22–24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg RCS Luxembourg B 118 349 as payment provider. The submission of payment details is necessary for performing payment services.

  12. ###### Collection of usage data, anonymized user-profiles

To optimize our website, we collect and save data, such as the time and data page is accessed, the page from which you opened our page, etc. This will be done anonymously without personally identifying the user of the page. User profiles may be created using pseudonyms. Nor does this data establish a connection to the natural persons behind the pseudonym. We also use cookies for the collected user data and to collect and store user data. These are small text files that are saved onto your computer and that are used to save statistical information, such as your operating system, Internet program (browser), IP address, your last opened website (referrer URL) and the time of day. We will only collect such data for statistical purposes to optimize our online presence and make our offers even more attractive. Data collection and storage will always be anonymized or pseudonymized and will not allow any inferences to be made about you as a natural person. For details on cookies see also section 13 below.

  13. ###### Usage of cookies

Cookies are used to offer certain services (e.g., saving session IDs, auto-login, item lists). After receiving a respective notice on the front page, you declare your acceptance to our use of cookies by visiting our website.

Cookies are small amounts of data which are saved onto your computer by your Internet browser. Information on your visit to our Internet platform may be saved in cookies. The most important cookies regarding analyzing tool, social media plug-ins, trackers are outlined in more details under sec. 14 below.

    * Strictly necessary cookies: Cookies required for the operation of our website. They are used to provide content to you, as a user, to navigate our website (e.g. ASP.NET_SessionID) and to provide services that you have requested e.g. the usage of our customer care / RMA services or payment (e.g. PayPal). Such cookies collect personal data in the form of IP address, location data payment data and identify you as long as you are logged into our website. These cookies are deleted when you close your browser session.
    * Analytical / performance cookies: These cookies allow us to recognize how many users visit our Internet platform and how they navigate across our pages (e.g. Alexa Metrics, Pingdom, Google-Analytics). These statistics are used for internal purposes to help us to test and improve functionality. While these cookies do not identify you personally while you are not logged in, they will collect your browser information and anonymized data, for the purposes outlined above. Analytical /performance cookies are valid for various periods and can be deleted in the browser settings at any time.
    * Functional cookies: These cookies are used to recognize you when you return to our website and allow us to remember you for an improved convenience or more features (e.g. IID, IdentifyKey, viewType). These cookies remember personal settings and preferences and collect the data saved in such settings. Functional cookies expire after a maximum of 2 years or can be deleted from your browser history at any time before their expiry.
    * Targeting cookies: These cookies record which pages you visited and on which links you clicked while visiting our website and are used to link to social media or display advertising tailored to your interest. Targeting cookies are valid for various periods.

The standard settings of most browsers are set to accept cookies. However, you can configure your browser so that it will reject some or all cookies or will ask for prior confirmation. However, if you reject all cookies, you may not be able to use all of our services without interruption.

  14. ###### Analyzing Tools, Social Media Plug-ins, Trackers

    1. ###### Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. You find more information concerning the treatment of user data by Google Analytics in Google's Privacy Policy: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2700409?hl=en 

In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will truncate/anonymize the last four numbers of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. On behalf of the website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

Furthermore, you can prevent collection by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. This will install an opt-out cookie that will prevent future collection of your data on this part of the website: Deactivate Google Analytics https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en

    2. ###### Facebook

On our pages, plugins of the social network Facebook (Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, California, 94025, USA) are integrated. The Facebook plugin you can see the Facebook logo or the "Like Button" ("Like") on our side. An overview of the Facebook-plugins here: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>.

When you visit our pages, the plugin establishes a connection between your browser and the Facebook server is established. Facebook receives the information that you have with your IP address visited our site. If you click on the Facebook "Like" button while you are logged into your Facebook account, you can link the content of our pages to your Facebook profile. Thereby Facebook can assign your visit to our site with your user account. We point out that we as providers of the site have no knowledge of the content of the transmitted data and use of that data through Facebook. For more information, please see the privacy policy of Facebook <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>. If you do not wish that Facebook can assign your visit to our pages to your Facebook account, please log out from your Facebook account.

    3. ###### Twitter

Functions of the Twitter service are integrated on our website. These functions are offered by Twitter Inc., Twitter, Inc. 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Through the use of Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" the web pages you visit are linked to your Twitter account and made known to other users. This data is also transmitted to Twitter.

We point out that as providers of the sites we have no knowledge of the content of the transmitted data and use of it through Twitter. For more information, see in the privacy statement of Twitter: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>.

Your privacy settings on Twitter, you can change the account settings under <https://twitter.com/account/settings>.

    4. ###### Youtube

Our website uses plugins of the Google-operated website YouTube. Provider of the website is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. If you visit one of our website having a YouTube-plugin embedded, a connection to YouTube servers will be established. The YouTube server will then be submitted the information that you have visited our websites.

If you are logged on to your YouTube account, you enable YouTube to associate your browsing behavior with your personal profile. You may prevent this by logging out of YouTube.

You find further information concerning the treatment of user data in the Privacy Policy of YouTube under: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy>.

    5. ###### Instagram

Plugins of the social network Instagram have been integrated in our website. Instagram is operated by Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ( "Instagram").

When you click the Instagram Button on our website while you are logged on to your Instagram account, you can link the contents of our website pages to your Instagram profile. This enables Instagram to assign your visit to our website to your user account. We point out that that as providers of the sites are not informed of the contents of the transmitted data and their use by Instagram.

For further information on the Privacy Policy of Instagram, refer to <https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/>.

  15. ###### IT Security and encryption

Your personal data transmitted to us during a purchase via our website will be stored on password and firewall protected servers and will be encrypted with digital security measures at a best practices level. Any personal data you submit to us during a purchase will be transmitted via SSL encryption technology.

However, even if we already establish a high level of data security with above mentioned measures, definite security may not be guaranteed in the internet. Therefore, we recommend you to install additional necessary and useful protections to your internet connection, such as password, sufficient anti-virus software as well as a secure browser.

  16. ###### Data subject's rights

You always have the followings right:

    * access to your personal data, their origin and recipients and the purpose of data processing, free of charge (Art. 15 GDPR),
    * rectification of your personal data (Art. 16 GDPR), 
    * erasure of your personal data (Art. 17 GDPR)
    * restriction of processing of your personal data (Art. 18 GDPR). 
    * right to data portability, which means the right to obtain the personal data relating to you that you have provided to us in a structured, common and machine-readable format (Art. 20 GDPR).

You may ask us at any time and at your sole discretion to object processing of your personal data (Art. 21 GDPR).

You may also revoke a consent granted by you for the processing and use of your data, which is not necessary owing to a superordinate legal regulation or directly for the processing of an existing contractual relationship, at all times.

Upon request, we will inform you if and which personal data we have stored about you in accordance with applicable law.

Any request for erasure of personal data may also be placed via our online form provided under [www.evga.com/erasure](https://www.evga.com/erasure/). You may submit any enquiry or request regarding the data subject's rights mentioned above via email [dataprotection@evga.com](mailto:dataprotection@evga.com) or by telephone 714-528-4500.

  17. ###### Deletions of accounts

Deletions of accounts will be carried out if and to the extent that all transactions under the respective account have been completed and closed. Notwithstanding the foregoing, EVGA remains entitled to store such data required to comply with statutory provisions and legal obligations to which EVGA is subject or for other legitimate interests of EVGA.

With deletion of an account, every and all "EVGA-bucks" earned under the respective account will be cancelled in full without any right to claim for compensation or replacement.

  18. ###### Filing a Complaint

If you are not satisfied with how we handle your personal data, you are entitled to file a complaint to your local Data Protection Authority.
